Thomas Chestnut

Glenolden, PA • (267) 324-9101

Email: thomaschestnut00@gmail.com • LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thomas-chestnut

Portfolio: tchestnut85.github.io • GitHub: github.com/tchestnut85

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer specializing in the MERN stack. Experienced in front-end and back-end development utilizing methods such as Agile development, MVC pattern, and RESTful APIs & GraphQL APIs. Proficient in JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, HTML5, CSS3, and MongoDB, among other technologies.

SKILLS

Front-End Skills: JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, AJAX, Handlebars, Jest, Redux

Back-End Skills: Node.js, Express.js, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, GraphQL, Apollo Server, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas

Other Skills: Agile Development, Git, RESTful APIs, GraphQL APIs, JavaScript OOP, MVC Structure, SPAs, PWAs, Test-Driven Development (Jest), Webpack

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania LPS Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development (Expected Feb 2021, Current Grade: A+) July 2020 - February 2021

Temple University, Philadelphia PA - Bachelor's Degree

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Studies August 2003 - May 2008

EXPERIENCE

Spark Therapeutics — EHS Associate

Philadelphia, PA June 2019 - Present

- Managed hazardous waste programs at multiple sites and associated recordkeeping and reporting.
- Collaborated with EHS team members to ensure laboratory safety processes and procedures are adhered to.
- Communicated with laboratory staff regarding safety or compliance issues and resolutions.
- Inspected laboratory area for safety and waste management compliance.

Triumvirate Environmental at GlaxoSmithKline — Assistant Program Manager

King of Prussia/Collegeville, PA

May 2017 - June 2019

- Managed team members and hazardous waste programs at multiple sites.
- Performed safety inspections as well as various regulatory environmental monitoring and sampling.
- Trained team members on various job functions.

Triumvirate Environmental at GlaxoSmithKline — Senior Environmental Specialist

King of Prussia/Collegeville, PA

January 2016 - May 2017

- Packaged laboratory chemical waste to meet regulatory requirements for shipment and disposal.
- Scheduled and performed waste shipments in conjunction with transportation vendors.